# Ashlesh Umesh Khajbage

+1 (312) 937 4635 | akhajbage@hawk.iit.edu | linkedin.com/in/ashleshk | github.com/Ashleshk | Chicago, IL 60616

## Summary

Data enthusiast with 2 years of experience in Data Analysis, Relational Databases, SQL, and ETL technologies. Demonstrated expertise in ad-hoc analysis, reporting, time-series analysis, data mining and ML. Google Data Analytics certified analyst aiming to implement analytical and data visualization skills to derive data insights gathered through analysis and reporting into efficient solutions for improving decision making.

### Skills

Functional Skills Data Analysis | Business Analysis | ETL | Data Visualization | Data Integration | Data Modelling | RDBMS

Programming Languages: Python | SQL | R | Java | NoSQL | Angular 8 | SAS

Databases MySQL | Oracle PL/SQL | Microsoft SQL Server | PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Machine Learning | Clustering | Data Wrangling | Statistical Analysis | Predictive Modeling | Classification

Visualization Tableau | Power BI | MS Excel | R-Tidyverse

Cloud Computing AWS | Snowflake | Amazon Redshift

Certifications/Trainings Google Data Analytics | IBM Data Science | Google BI Analyst | SAS Visual Analytics

Soft Skills Problem-solving | Team Player | Communication | Time Management | Detail-oriented

Education

Master of Science in Data Science, Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago

Aug 2022 - May 2024

Courses: Data preparation & Analysis, Statistical learning, Machine learning, and Big data technologies Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication, *University of Pune, India* 

GPA: 3.66

Aug 2016 – Jun 2020

# **Professional Experience**

### Data Scientist Intern, Calamus Investment

May 2023 - Present

- Analyzing financial data to uncover marketplace relationships and trends, providing competitive advantage.
- Deriving strategic decision-making by analyzing asset allocation, ETF trends, and category preferences of Calamos' top 10 firms.

## Data Analyst Intern, GlobalShala

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

- Collaborated with 8 data analysts across countries to boost social media engagement by 60% and reduce advertising costs by 30%.
- Cataloged **exploratory data analysis:** visualization and documentation for the project in form of infographics and 2 project reports.
- Designed a social media dashboard using **Tableau** to track key performance indicators and optimize content/ads.

## Software Engineer - Cloud Analytics, LTIMindtree

Oct 2020 - Jul 2022

- Effectively communicated results, strategies with stakeholders directly along with team members.
- Gathered Insurance Client requirements and automated 150+ Batch Scripts for 10+ policy source systems on Autosys.
- Daily exploratory ad-hoc data analysis from cross-functional teams on SharePoint and provided detailed analytical support.
- Improved SQL query efficiency by 40% through optimization and fine-tuning.
- Developed real-time cloud dashboards in Dynatrace and resolved 150+ issues through root-cause analysis within client deadlines.
- Created data visualization dashboards in MS Excel to provide data-driven insights to clients resulting in increased profitability by 30%.

# **Projects**

## Cryptocurrency Market Evaluation | R

• Using large volume of cryptocurrencies data and news article from wrangling, developed a sophisticated cryptocurrency market Evaluator by designing a natural language processing models along with visualizing data using R libraries.

## Emotion Classification of Product Reviews on Twitter | Python, TensorFlow, AWS Sagemaker

• Performed performance analysis of deep learning models (BERT, Roberta, RNN) to classify large Twitter data into 6 emotions on AWS Sagemaker, achieving best 97.83% accuracy and 0.83 F1-score with RNN model. Showed visualization using word cloud libraries.

## Vehicle Detection using Aerial Imagery | Python, OpenCV, Tensorflow

• Developed a simulation tool to optimize vehicle classification (6 classes) in Aerial Imagery dataset using CNN model, achieving 92.6% precision on real-time data collected from drones.

### Zillow Real Estate Data Analysis | Python, Tableau

Performed data preprocessing and analysis to analyze daily real estate consumer queries using Python and visualize insights using Tableau.
 Designed an interactive website using real-time data for consumers to compare predicted housing prices with Zillow estimate for better decision making.

## Netflix Media Database Application | MySQL

• Constructed a complete database management system for Netflix media streaming application in MySQL by implementing cardinality constraints, entity relationship diagrams, logical relationship model, DDL statements and complex SQL queries.